

Federico Montero

React Developer | Musician

Personal Profile

My name is Federico Montero, I am 37 years old, and I live with my partner and daughter in Montevideo, Uruguay. Music has been my primary activity throughout my life until 2021 when I made the decision to radically change my career path and venture into the IT field as a programmer.

I consider myself a patient person; I always seek to understand how things work, and I have a passion for cars.

Educational Training

Coding Bootcamp

Hack Academy

3-month educational program, extremely practical and full-time dedication (+600 hours). Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

Front-End

Hack Academy

Intensive course where I learned the fundamentals of HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Dedication: 60 hours Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

Frontend Development Industry Training

Brainnest

Frontend Development Industry Training of 4 weeks (24 hours + Individual Work) Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Work Experience

Software Developer

Cencosud SA - QA Developer

• Feb 2023 - May 2024

Digital Operations VCP DevOps Team

TCS - General Electric Helathcare

• Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

Sound and Music Education Teacher

The Anglo School

- Jul 2021 Dec 2021.
- 1st y 2nd Ciclo Básico.

Technologies

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript (ES6+)
- Typescript
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- React.js
- Redux
- Git | GitHub | GitLab
- Nest.js
- MySQL
- AWS
- New Relic
- Kubernetes
- Jira

Languages

- English (FCE)
- Spanish (Native)

Contact Cel: +598 99 279 185 Links LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/fede-montero

Email: federicomontero86@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/federicomontero86

Ubication: Montevideo, Uruguay Final Proyect (Coding Bootcamp):

Laderhack - Ecommerce